<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michael Brown</title>
    <link>http://michael-brown.net/tags/ios/index.xml</link>
    <description>Recent content on Michael Brown</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>Copyright © 2016</copyright>
    <atom:link href="http://michael-brown.net/tags/ios/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Apple vs the FBI</title>
      <link>http://michael-brown.net/2016/apple-vs-the-fbi/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://michael-brown.net/2016/apple-vs-the-fbi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The details of this case have been broken down and explained extremely well by &lt;a href=&#34;https://stratechery.com/2016/apple-the-fbi-and-security/&#34;&gt;Ben Thompson&lt;/a&gt;. The more technical details have also been very thoroughly covered by &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.zdziarski.com/blog/&#34;&gt;Jonathan Zdziarski&lt;/a&gt; on his blog.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am clearly on Apple&amp;rsquo;s side in this battle, and very much hope that they don&amp;rsquo;t lose. However, it&amp;rsquo;s worth pointing out that if they were to lose, that is, if they were compelled to provide a mechanism to facilitate brute force pass code cracking it wouldn&amp;rsquo;t be a total disaster. All anyone would need to do to keep their iPhone secure would be use a longer numeric passcode or, even better, an alpha numeric passcode. A 10 digit passcode would take several years to brute force, rather than several hours for a 6 digit one. A 10 character alpha numeric passcode would take thousands of years to crack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So, any clued up user (criminal or otherwise) who wants to keep their iPhone secure against GovtOS just needs to use a longer passcode to make it impossible to crack in a useful time period. With Touch ID, the inconvenience of a long passcode is hugely reduced, so I would strongly recommend it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>